<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>R Markdown on Practical R</title>
    <link>/tags/r-markdown/</link>
    <description>Recent content in R Markdown on Practical R</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2019 21:13:14 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/r-markdown/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction</title>
      <link>/intro-practical-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2019 21:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/intro-practical-r/</guid>
      <description>IntroductionData VisualizationData ScienceIntroductionAre you struggling to learn R so you can create beautiful and effect data visualizations and produce data science projects that add value?
You are not alone. Analyzing data is now common to a lot of professions that may not have any background in programming or computer science.
Are you full of excitement for your new R project but finding it difficult to quickly achieve the results you want and need?
Coming from a background in other programming languages may be problematic because R does some things a little bit differently.
Are you taking a course in R and finding that you can’t keep up with the class and need some background?
Or are you just interested in learning more about R and what R can do?
I would like to help you do more with R.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Practical R</title>
      <link>/about-practical-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about-practical-r/</guid>
      <description>Practical RD.J. ForbesPractical RPractical R, the blog, is built using Hugo, an open source static site generator available under the Apache Licence 2.0.. Hugo provides the ability to combine Markdown, R Markdown and HTML content files and uses shortcodes for adding rich content. This lets me focus on the content, not the blog.
Websites built with Hugo are extremely fast, secure and can be deployed anywhere.
Learn more or contribute on GitHub.
D.J. ForbesI have a passion for data science and the transformative power of data visualization and design to simplify and elevate communication and to engage and inspire people everywhere.
I first encountered R as a graduate student working on my Ph.D in 2011. I was looking for a tool to do analysis of a spatio-temporal data set. Commercial Geographic Information Systems (GIS) are not capable of doing that kind of analysis.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>